Hello and welcome to real easyy English from BBC Learning English Each week we have a real conversation in easy English
To help you learn I'm Phil and I'm Beer you can find a video version of this podcast on our website along with a free worksheet subtitles
And a transcript that's@ BBClearningenglish.com. .
So how are things becca yeah things are going really well thank you Phil we've just had a really lovely weekend very sunny,
Very nice how are things for you well they're very good as you said it was a very sunny weekend and yeah I love the sunshine I love it when the weather is a bit warmer
And that's what we're going to be talking about today we're going to be talking about hot weather and what you do to stay cool.
Yeah I love hot weather'very excited for summer to come here soon I really enjoy eating ice cream
When it is very hot that helps me to stay cool.
Yeah, are there any other things are there any activities that you do when when the weather's hot you eat apart from eating ice apart from eating I really don't
Like being hot when I'm in the city because I feel like, U the heat kind of stays and it's very difficult to find like a swimming pool or I love
To go to the beach, I think being in water can really help you cool down how about yourself when it's really hot?
When we get a heat wave, which is when you get a few days and it's a long way above normal temperatures, then I like to put a paddling pool in the back garden, which is like a little swimming pool.
And you just fill it with water and then jump in yeah, water can really help you cool off or cool down to become cold so how do you make the most of hot weather then
Because you mentioned we don't have, Many days of very hot weather here in the UK, I spend a lot more time outside than I do during
The winter, for example.
If we got nice warm weather and it's not raining, it's nice to be outside just to sit, spend some time reading, whatever cooking outside.
Having a barbecue, eating outside, could sit in the garden and eat dinner outside, all of those things you can do in the summer when it's warm and of course, when it's not raining.
But that sounds lovely, really making the most of those long hot days, so to make the most of something is to do as much as you can within the time or the space.
That you're in if it's a very hot day, do you prefer to be outside in the sun or to be inside near a fan or near the air conditioner
Okay, yeah, yeah I prefer to be outside I remember going on holiday with my friends and they wanted to stay
Inside shopping centres where there was an aircon and AC but I wanted to be Al and walk.
Although it's very important that if you are outside when it's very hot that you drink water and you find places where you can cool
Down it depends as well on the country as well I guess because in England the summers are never very very hot but in other parts of the world I guess it can probably be quite dangerous
Yes yeah and also adding on to that because it isn't very hot often.
In the UK in England, we aren't very well prepared for the heat so yeah,
If you do come and visit the UK just know that on a very, very hot day, it could be quite difficult to find an area that does have a fan or air conditioning.
Okay, let's recap the vocabulary that we heard during the conversation starting with heat wave Now a heat wave is a period
Of time with very hot weather If you make the most of something you enjoy it as much as you can for example,
I make the most of hot days by going outside for walks and getting an ice cream We also heard cool down which means,
To feel less hot so for example, when it's really hot, I like to cool down by jumping in a paddling pool and we can also say
Cool off which means the same in this context.
And we had air conditioning that is a machine that helps the space that you're in so it could be your house or your work office, it helps that space feel less hot, it helps it feel colder.
You might hear it shortened to Aircon or AC That's it for this episode of real easy English the worksheet on our website to test what you've learned and that's at BBC learningning English.
And we'll see you next week with another real conversation in easyy English but for now it's goodbye bye.